Second Round Questions for Zoho
	
	>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>GEEKSORGEEKS SET---36<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<



1.	Given a text and a wildcard pattern, implement wildcard pattern matching algorithm that finds if wildcard pattern is matched with text. 
	The matching should cover the entire text (not partial text).
	The wildcard pattern can include the characters ‘?’ and ‘*’
	‘?’ – matches any single character
	‘*’ – Matches any sequence of characters (including the empty sequence).

2. {{DONE}}	Given an input string and a dictionary of words, 
	find out if the input string can be segmented into a space-separated sequence of dictionary words. See following examples for more details.
	Example : Consider the following dictionary 
		  { i, like, sam, sung, samsung, mobile, ice, cream, icecream, man, go, mango}
		Input:  ilike
		Output: Yes 
		The string can be segmented as "i like".

		Input:  ilikesamsung
		Output: Yes
		The string can be segmented as "i like samsung" or "i like sam sung".<>
3.	Print the following pattern

   1  
  3 2
 6 5 4
10 9 8 7
10 9 8 7 
 6 5 4 
  3 2 
   1


4. {{DONE}}	Given an array as input, The condition is if the number is repeated you must add the number and put the next index value to 0. If the number is 0 print it at the last.
	Example: Eg: arr[] = { 0, 2, 2, 2, 0, 6, 6, 0, 8}
			Output: 4 2 12 8 0 0 0 0 0 .

>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>>GEEKSORGEEKS SET---36<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<<
{{{{DONE}}}}}}
Given a set of numbers like <10, 36, 54,89,12> we want to find sum of weights based on the following conditions
    1. 5 if a perfect square
    2. 4 if multiple of 4 and divisible by 6
    3. 3 if even number

And sort the numbers based on the weight and print it as follows

<10,its_weight>,<36,its weight><89,its weight>



 

Should display the numbers based on increasing order.

3. {{{DONE}}}	Save the string “WELCOMETOZOHOCORPORATION” in a two dimensional array and search for substring like “too” in the two dimensional string both from left to right and from top to bottom.

w	e	L	C	O
M	E	T	O	Z
O	H	O	C	O
R	P	O	R	A
oppp
"{ IIT	I	O	n	  
And print the start and ending index as

Start index : <1,2>

End index: <3, 2>

4.	{{DONE}} Given a 9×9 sudoku we have to evaluate it for its correctness. We have to check both the sub matrix correctness and the whole sudoku correctness.

5.	Given a two dimensional array of string like

  <”luke”, “shaw”>
  <”wayne”, “rooney”>
  <”rooney”, “ronaldo”>
  <”shaw”, “rooney”> 
Where the first string is “child”, second string is “Father”. And given “ronaldo” we have to find his no of grandchildren Here “ronaldo” has 2 grandchildren. So our output should be 2.


1) Alternate sorting: Given an array of integers, rearrange the array in such a way that the first element is first maximum and second element is first minimum.

    Eg.) Input  : {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7}
         Output : {7, 1, 6, 2, 5, 3, 4} 
2) Remove unbalanced parentheses in a given expression.

    Eg.) Input  : ((abc)((de))
         Output : ((abc)(de))  

         Input  : (((ab)
         Output : (ab) 
3) Form a number system with only 3 and 4. Find the nth number of the number system.
Eg.) The numbers are: 3, 4, 33, 34, 43, 44, 333, 334, 343, 344, 433, 434, 443, 444, 3333, 3334, 3343, 3344, 3433, 3434, 3443, 3444 ….

4) Check whether a given mathematical expression is valid.

    Eg.) Input  : (a+b)(a*b)
         Output : Valid

         Input  : (ab)(ab+)
         Output : Invalid

         Input  : ((a+b)
         Output : Invalid 
I don’t remember the 5th question.









. Write a program to give the following output for the given input

Eg 1: Input: a1b10
       Output: abbbbbbbbbb
Eg: 2: Input: b3c6d15
          Output: bbbccccccddddddddddddddd
The number varies from 1 to 99.
2. Write a program to sort the elements in odd positions in descending order and elements in ascending order



 

Eg 1: Input: 13,2 4,15,12,10,5
        Output: 13,2,12,10,5,15,4
Eg 2: Input: 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9
        Output: 9,2,7,4,5,6,3,8,1 
3. Write a program to print the following output for the given input. You can assume the string is of odd length

Eg 1: Input: 12345
       Output:
1       5
  2   4
    3
  2  4
1      5
Eg 2: Input: geeksforgeeks
         Output:
g                         s
  e                     k
    e                 e
      k             e
        s         g
          f      r
             o
          f     r
        s         g
      k             e
    e                 e
  e                      k
g                          s 
4. Find if a String2 is substring of String1. If it is, return the index of the first occurrence. else return -1.

Eg 1:Input:
        String 1: test123string
         String 2: 123
        Output: 4
Eg 2: Input:
        String 1: testing12
        String 2: 1234 
        Output: -1
5. Given two sorted arrays, merge them such that the elements are not repeated

Eg 1: Input:
        Array 1: 2,4,5,6,7,9,10,13
        Array 2: 2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,11,15
       Output:
       Merged array: 2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,13,15 
6. Using Recursion reverse the string such as

Eg 1: Input: one two three
      Output: three two one
Eg 2: Input: I love india
      Output: india love I 


Print the given pattern:
Input:
N= 3, M=3
Output:
X X X
X 0 X
X X X

Input:
N=4 M=5
Output:
X X X X
X 0 0 X
X 0 0 X
X 0 0 X
X X X X

Input:
N=6 M=7
X X X X X X
X 0 0 0 0 X
X 0 X X 0 X
X 0 X X 0 X
X 0 X X 0 X
X 0 0 0 0 X
X X X X X X

2) To find the number of groups and output the groups:
Explanation: To find the sum of the elements in the groups and that sum should be divisible by input X and the groups should be limited to range with X numbers.
If X is 3, then the group should have only 2 elements and 3 elements from the array whose sum is divisible by 3.
Input:
Array: 3, 9, 7, 4, 6, 8
X: 3
Output:
3, 9
3, 6
9, 6
3, 9, 6
No of groups: 4

Level three:
1) To output the given string for the given input which is an integer.
Input: 1
Output: A
Input: 26
Output: Z
Input : 27
Output: AA
Input: 28:
Output: AB
Input: 1000
Output: ALL

2) Input:
Number of elements in set1: 4
Elements are: 9, 9, 9, 9
Number of elements in set 2: 3
Elements are: 1,1,1
Output:
1, 0, 1, 1, 0
Input:
Number of elements in set1: 11
Elements are: 7,2,3,4,5,3,1,2,7,2,8
Number of elements in set 2: 3
Elements are: 1,2,3
Output: 7,2,3,4,5,3,1,2,8,5,1



Program 1:
Help john to find new friends in social network
Input:
3
Mani 3 ram raj guna
Ram 2 kumar Kishore
Mughil 3 praveen Naveen Ramesh

Output:
Raj guna kumar Kishore praveen Naveen Ramesh



 

Program 2:
Input:
With the starting and ending time of work given find the minimum no of workers needed

Start time 		end time
1230			0130
1200			0100
1600			1700
Output:
2

Program 3:
Find the union intersection of two list and also find except (remove even elements from list1 and odd elements from list2)
Input

List 1: 1,3,4,5,6,8,9
List 2: 1, 5,8,9,2

Union: 1, 3,4,5,6,8,9,2
Intersection: 1,5,8,9
Except: 1, 3, 5,9,8,2 
Program 4:



 

Rotate the matrix elements
For 3*3 matrix
Input
1	2	3
4	5	6
7	8	9

Output:
4	1	2
7	5	3
8	9	6

For 4*4 matrix
Input:
1	2	3	4	
5	6	7	8
9	10	11	12
13	14	15	16

Output:
5	1	2	3
9	10	6	4
13	11	7	8
14	15	16	12
Program 5:
Find the largest possible prime number with given no
Input
5
4691
Output:
9461

Round 3:
For one batch of people
Basic programs like pattern printing
1
22
333
4444
And
1
2 4
3 5 7
6 8 10 12




. Given dates in day,month, year order sort them.



 

Q2. Given a string of integers find out all the possible words that can made out of it in continuous order. Eg: 11112

ans: AAAAB
AKAB
AAKB
AAAL etc.

Q3: Find whether a given number is magic number or not. It is something which gives same digits even after cubing it.

Q4: something related to rotating an array.



 

Q5: Given two numbers and an operation either + or – , perform the operation.
Now remove any zeros if present in the two numbers and perform an operation. See if the result obtained is same or not after removing zero’s in the original result.




A 3 hour programming round. (offline method)
Once u complete a question , it shall be verified for given sample test cases and 4 or 5 pre verified test cases. To get the next question every test case has to be solved. The questions were challenging and explanation was good



 

the various questions were
1. Cyclic number verification
2. Sorting dates
3. write a code to solve given mathematical expression
4. generation of unique number from any random number
5. given a number u need to print all combination of aphabets for that number





 Spiral printing.
O/P
4444444
4333334
4322234
4321234
4322234
4333334
4444444

2. Sort the array alternately i.e first element should be max value, second min value, third second max, third second min. Eg: arr[] = {1,2,3,4,5,6,7} O/P: {7,1,6,2,5,3,4} Note: no extra space and time complexity should be less;



 

3. Print all the substring of the given string.

4. Print the numbers which are mismatched from two array. Arr1 = {a b c d e f g h i}
arr2 ={ a b d e e g g i i}, O/P- cd, de, f, g, h, i.

5. Print all possible combinations from the given string.





Given two sorted arrays output a merged array without duplicates.
Array1: [1, 2, 3, 6, 9]
Array2: [2, 4, 5, 10]
Merged Array: [1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 9, 10]

Question 2: Given a sliding window of size k print the maximum of the numbers under the sliding window.
Example: Consider a sliding window of size k equals 3. Let the array be [3,2,7,6,5,1,2,3,4] the output should print 7 as the first output as first window contains {3,2,7} and second window contains {2,7,6} and so on and the final output is {7,7,7,6,5,3,4}

Question 3: Given a array with n elements print the number of occurrences of that number each number in that array. The order of number doesn’t matter. You can reorder the elements.
Example : [2,1,3,2,2,5,8,9,8]
Output:
2-3
1-1
3-1
5-1
8-2
9-1

Question 4: Enter two strings from command line and check whether any substring present in first string that follows the pattern of second sting.. They asked to implement  regular expressions for * and backslash without built in functions.



 

“abcd” “a*cd” answer : yes
“aaaa” “a*”  answer : yes
“a*c” “a\*c” answer:yes
“adsd” “ad” answer:no

Question 5: They gave a passage and the output should be printing out the number of occurrence of each word and the indices it occurs without using string matching

The passage given was “jana Gana Mana” and so on.. and we have to print number of jana and it’s indices.i.e at which position it occurs.

I have completed first and 5th program. The programs were not of equal weight-age. 4th and 5th were given more weight-age. They gave importance with the way of approach. Another guy solved the first 4 programs but he is not selected because of his inefficient code. And I got selected to the next round just because of the appropriate data structure and logic the applied.

Given two numbers a and b both < 200 we have to find the square numbers which lie between a and b(inclusive)

eg) i/p a = 20;b = 100;
      o/p 25,36,49,64,81,100 
2.Alternately sort an unsorted array..



 

eg) i/p {5,2,8,7,4,3,9}
      o/p {9,2,8,3,7,4,5}
3. Given an array and a threshold value find the o/p

eg) i/p {5,8,10,13,6,2};threshold = 3;
      o/p  count = 17
      explanation:
Number	parts	            counts
5	            {3,2}                 2
8                      {3,3,2}              3
10                    {3,3,3,1}           4
13                    {3,3,3,3,1}        5
6                      {3,3}                 2
2                      {2}                    1 
4.a. Given two binary numbers add the two numbers in binary form without converting them to decimal value.

eg) a = 1010 b = 11001
      o/p  100011	            
  b.The two numbers were given in base n 
	eg) a = 123  b = 13  n = 4
	      o/p  202
5.Write a program to print the below pattern

for n = 6
	1	7	12	16	19	21
	2	8	13	17	20
	3	9	14	18	
	4	10	15
	5	11	
	6 
6.Given bigger NxN matrix and a smaller MxM matrix print TRUE if the smaller matrix can be found in the bigger matrix else print FALSE



 

7.Given two matrices a and b both of size NxN find if matrix a can be transformed to matrix b by rotating it 90deg , 180deg , 270deg if so print TRUE else print FALSE

8 In addition to the above question you have to check if matrix a can be transformed by mirroring vertically or horizontally to matrix b.

I solved 7 questions .. Those who solved more than 5 were selected for the next round.


Round 3 : TIME : 3hrs
About 50 – 60 were shortlisted .. This round was also a programming round..
Questions were based of matrix transformation.Each question was an extension of the previous question in some way..There were 5 questions .. I solved only 2 🙁 But got selected for the next round , I think it was based on my performance on all previous rounds..


You’re given an array. Print the elements of the array which are greater than its previous elements in the array.
Input : 2, -3, -4, 5, 9, 7, 8    Output: 2 5 9You should solve this question in O(n) time.
You’re given an even number n. If n=4, you have to print the following pattern :44444334
4334

4444



 

If n=6, then the pattern should be like this :

666666

655556

654456

654456

655556

666666

You’re given a number n. If write all the numbers from 1 to n in a paper, we have to find the number of characters written on the paper.For example if n=13, the output should be 18 if n = 101, the output should be 195
A number is called as binary-decimal if all the digits in the number should be either ‘1’ or ‘0’. Any number can be written as a sum of binary-decimals. Our task is to find the minimum number of binary-decimals to represent a number.Input : 32Output : 10 11 11
Input : 120

Output : 10 110

You’re given a string as an input. You have to reverse the string by keeping the punctuation and spaces. You have to modify the source string itself with creating an another string.
Input :A man, in the boat says : I see 1-2-3 in the sky


1) Given a number, convert it into corresponding alphabet.



 

Input Output
       1     A
      26     Z
      27     AA
      676     ZZZ
2) Given a Roman numeral, find its corresponding decimal value.
https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/converting-roman-numerals-decimal-lying-1-3999/
3) Write a program to print all permutations of a given string. Note here you need to take all combinations as well, say for the input ABC the output should be as follows:

Input: ABC
Output:
A
B C
AB AC BA BC CA CB
ABC ACB BCA BAC CBA CAB
4) Write a program to rotate an n*n matrix 90,180,270,360 degree.
https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/inplace-rotate-square-matrix-by-90-degrees/ is the solution for rotating a matrix 90 degree. For rotating the matrix 180,270,360 degree, u need to call the same method 2,3,4 times based on the input.

5) https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/reverse-words-in-a-given-string/

6) Write a program to convert a number into a mono-digit number.

Conditions:
a) You are allowed to add and subtract the consecutive digits (starting from left).
b) You are allowed to do only one operation on a digit.
c) You cannot perform any operation on a resultant digit of the previous operation.
d) Your code should also find if a given number cannot be converted to a mono digit number.

      Input     Output
    72581         7(2+5)81
                  77(8-1)
                  777
    3962          cannot create a mono digit number
8 people cleared this round. They didn’t see any optimization in this round. Simply, completing 4 or more questions will get you through to the next round. The interviewers helped us to find some rare corner cases too if we miss anything.










Given an array, find the minimum of all the greater numbers for each element in the
array.

   
Sample: 
Array : {2, 3, 7, ­1, 8, 5, 11} 
   
Output: 
{2­>3, 3­>5, 7­>8, ­1­>2, 8­>11, 5­>7, 11­>} 
2) Find the largest sum contiguous subarray which should not have negative numbers. We have to print the sum and the corresponding array elements which brought up the
sum.



 

 
Sample: 
Array : {­2, 7, 5, ­1, 3, 2, 9, ­7} 

Output: 
     Sum : 14 
     Elements : 3, 2, 9  
3) Given a string, we have to reverse the string without changing the position of punctuations and spaces.

 
Sample:   house no : 123@ cbe 
Output:    ebc32 1o :  nes@ uoh 
4) Given a 2D grid of characters, you have to search for all the words in a dictionary by
moving only along two directions, either right or down. Print the word if it occurs.

 
Sample :         
  a   z  o   l 
  n   x  h   o
  v   y   i   v 
  o   r   s  e 
 Dictionary = {van, zoho, love, are, is} 
 
 Output: 
    zoho 
    love 
    Is 
 
5) Given a string, change the order of words in the string (last string should come first).
Should use RECURSION

  
Sample:   one two three 
Output :  three two one 







Given an odd length word which should be printed from the middle of the word.
The output should be in the following pattern.
Example:

Input: PROGRAM
Output:
              G
            GR
          GRA
       GRAM
     GRAMP
   GRAMPR
GRAMPRO
2. It is a program to implement Least Recently Used (LRU) concept. Given a key, if it is already existed then it should be marked as recently used otherwise a value should be stored which is given as input and marked as recently used. The capacity is to store only 10 key, value pairs. If the table is full and given a new key; the key, value pair which is not recently used should be deleted which gives feasibility to store the new key, value pair.

3. Given a few pairs of names in the order child, father. The input is a person name and level number. The output should be the number of children in that particular level for the person given.
Example:
Input:
[
{Ram, Syam},
{Akil, Syam},
{Nikil, Ram},
{Subhash, Ram},
{Karthik, Akil}
];



 

Syam 2

Output: 3 (Syam has Ram and Akil in level 1 and in level 2 he have Nikil, Subhash, Karthik. So the answer is 3).

4. Given an array of positive integers. The output should be the number of occurrences of each number.
Example:
Input: {2, 3, 2, 6, 1, 6, 2}
Output:
1 – 1
2 – 3
3 – 1
6 – 2






GIven 2 huge numbers as seperate digits, store them in array
and process them and calculate the sum of 2 numbers and store
the result in an array and print the sum.

Input:
Number of digits:12
9 2 8 1 3 5 6 7 3 1 1 6
Number of digits:9
7 8 4 6 2 1 9 9 7
Output :
9 2 8 9 2 0 2 9 5 1 1 3

2.Given sorted array check if two numbers sum in it is a given

value
Input
Array = {1 3 4 8 10 } N = 7
output
true

3. Compiuting value of sin (x)
Input x = 30 n = 10
output = 0.5

Hint : The equation sin(x) = x – x^3 / 3! + x^5 / 5! – ….

4. Write function to find multipication of 2 numbers using +
operator You must use minimu possible iterations.

Input: 3 , 4
Output 12

5. Given array find maximum sum of contiguous sub array

{-2 -3 4 -1 -2 1 5 -3}

output 7 elements [ 4 -1 -2 1 5]

6. Given unsorted array find all combination of the element
for a given sum. Order should be maintained.

Input :
8 3 4 7 9 N=7
Output
{3 4 } {7}




 Write a program to determine whether a given number can be expressed as sum of two prime numbers or not.

For example 34 can be expressed as sum of two prime numbers but 23 cannot be.

Question 2 : Take a 2 or 3 digit input number, reverse it and add it to the original number until the obtained number is a palindrome or 5 iterations are completed.

Input : n = 32
Output : 55
23 + 32 = 55 which is a palindrome.

Input : 39
Output : 363

Question 3 : Given a string, reverse only vowels in it; leaving rest of the string as it is.

Input : abcdef
Output : ebcdaf

Question 4 : Write a program to check if the given words are present in matrix given below. The words can be left to right, top to bottom and the diagonals (in top to bottom direction)

zoho_interview

Question 5 : Write a program to form lines using given set of words. The line formation should follow below rules.

i) Total characters in a single line excluding the space between the words and the favorite character should not exceed the given number.

ii) Favorite character is case insensitive.

iii) Words should not be broken up. Complete words alone should be used in a single line. A word should be used in one line only.

Input : Max char per line = 10
        Favorite character = 'o'
        Words : Zoho, Eating, Watching, Pogo
                Loving, Mango
Output : Watching Zoho
         Eating Mango
         Loving Pogo.




1.Solve the equation X power Y with given values.

Example:
    Input: X=2, Y=-2
    Output: 0.25
2.Find the distance between two gievn points and round it to the nearest number.

Example:
    Input: (2,4)(4,10)
    Output: 6
3.Count the numbers of characters in the given string treating ‘$’ as escape sequence. If ‘$’ is preceeded by ”, consider it as normal ‘$’ and not the escape sequence. If ” occurs, treat it as single ”.

Example:
    Input: Hello$World$
    Output: 11
4.Given a 2D matrix, find the sum of all the elements.



 

Example:
    Input: [1 2 3]
           [4 5 6]
           [7 8 9]
    Output: 45
Level 2:
Finish one question to get the next type. Total 5 questions. (3 hours – machine round)
1.Solve the equation (XpowerY/Z!) + (Z/(X!+Z)) with given values of X, Y, Z. X and Z cannot be negative.

Example:
    Input: X=2, Y=3, Z=4
    Output: 1
2.Batman, Spiderman and Superman are going to start a business. The total investment is 1000M$. Anyone can add new investment to their existing investment. They can transfer investments between themselves. The program should be in OOP style and should have a menu for user to do all operations. (Something similar to below example.)

Constraints:
    a.Total investment should always be 
      equal to or lesser than 1000M$.
    b.Spiderman's investment should never
      exceed Batman's.
    c.Investment cannot go into negative.
    d.Display investments on each update.
Example:
    Input: batman = 300, spiderman = 250,
          superman = 100
    Output:
    batman - 300
    spiderman - 250
    superman - 100
    add 100 into spiderman
    sorry, spiderman cant have more 
    investment than batman add 200 
    to batman
    batman - 500
    spiderman - 250
    superman - 100
    add 500 to superman
    sorry, total investment cant 
    exceed 1000. 




  Find the minimum number of times required to represent a number as sum of squares.

12 = 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 
    1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 + 1^2 
12 = 2^2 + 2^2 + 2^2
12 = 3^2 + 1^2 + 1^2

Input: 12
Output: min: 3
2) Search a string in a given 2D matrix. And print its possible path.
allowed movements are right left up and down.

3) In a given pascal triangle find the possible triangles.

4) in a matrix find the number of rectangles filled with 1s.

Input:   0 1 1 0
         1 1 1 0
         0 0 1 1
         0 0 1 1

Output: 2.
5) There are n items each with a value and weight. A sack is filled with the weights. In other words there is an array with of length n having the values of the items arr[0…n-1] and another array with weight arr[0…n-1].
if a sack is to be filled with weight W find the minimum possible value subset.


